export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2001 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. When a large proportion of a country’s population is under fifteen years of age, the population is described as",
A: "old",
B: "young",
C: "declining",
D: "ageing",
answer: "B. young",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. The age of sex structure of a population is normally portrayed in the form of a population",
A: "Profile",
B: "pyramid",
C: "census",
D: "map",
answer: "B. pyramid",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. The sector of the economy in which the majority of Ghanaians are employed is",
A: "transportation",
B: "mining",
C: "agriculture",
D: "Manufacturing",
answer: "C. agriculture",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. The process by which the state withdraws from active involvement in economic activities is",
A: "decentralization",
B: "demonetization",
C: "devaluation",
D: "divestiture",
answer: "D. divestiture",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. The most important means of resolving conflicts in traditional society is through",
A: "agitation",
B: "resolution",
C: "arbitration",
D: "revolution",
answer: "C. arbitration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. Which of the following is a sexually transmitted disease",
A: "Syphilis",
B: "Meningitis",
C: "Buruli ulcer",
D: "Trypanosomiasis",
answer: "A. Syphilis",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. The concept of decentralization has been introduction Ghana to",
A: "help government appoint District Chief Executives",
B: "give chiefs the opportunity to exercise power",
C: "give employment to rural youth",
D: "promote grassroot participation in development",
answer: "D. promote grassroot participation in development",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. All the following are causes of teenage pregnancy except",
A: "high rate of population growth",
B: "financial predicament of families",
C: "irresponsible parenthood",
D: "Increasing decline of morality among the youth",
answer: "A. high rate of population growth",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. The residential arrangement where the newly married couple establishes their own household is termed",
A: "neolocal",
B: "duolocal",
C: "patrilocal",
D: "matrilocal",
answer: "A. neolocal",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. One of the informal ways of social control in traditional society was",
A: "imprisonment",
B: "starving",
C: "ostracism",
D: "arbitration",
answer: "C. ostracism",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. The increase in the rate of criminal activity in Ghana can be attributed mainly to",
A: "commercialisation and education",
B: "high rate of urbanization growth and migration",
C: "high rate of population growth and migration",
D: "Christianity and the disregard of the ancestor",
answer: "C. high rate of population growth and migration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. The only means by which adolescents can be completely protected from sexually transmitted diseases is through",
A: "the use of contraceptives",
B: "reduction in sexual activity",
C: "keeping one partner",
D: "sexual abstinence",
answer: "D. sexual abstinence",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. Which of the following socialization agents is very dominant during the formative years of a child?",
A: "The school",
B: "The peer group",
C: "The mass media",
D: "The family",
answer: "D. The family",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Which of the following organizations was setup after the First World War to bring about understanding and co-operation among nations?",
A: "The Organization of African Unity",
B: "The League of Nations",
C: "The United Nations Organization",
D: "The Non-Aligned Movement",
answer: "B. The League of Nations",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. In traditional society education provided the means for",
A: "transmitting common culture",
B: "obtaining jobs",
C: "inculcating human rights",
D: "emphasizing conservative values",
answer: "A. transmitting common culture",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. The age at first marriage has slightly increased as a result of",
A: "relaxation of taboos and rituals",
B: "religious indoctrination and monogamy",
C: "education and apprenticeship",
D: "reduced sexuality and high bride price",
answer: "C. education and apprenticeship",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. The majority of Ghanaians marry under",
A: "customary law",
B: "the ordinance",
C: "religious law",
D: "natural law",
answer: "A. customary law",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. Goal setting is important because",
A: "it enables one to achieve everything in life",
B: "it promotes proper planning",
C: "little time is spent on setting the goal",
D: "it is a well-known practice",
answer: "B. it promotes proper planning",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. It is important to develop rural areas since",
A: "they form part of the country",
B: "the people are poor",
C: "the bulk of the resources are located there",
D: "urban dwellers come from these areas",
answer: "C. the bulk of the resources are located there",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. A qualitative change in all aspects of the life of a people is described as",
A: "growth",
B: "inflation",
C: "deflation",
D: "development",
answer: "D. development",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. Low productivity in Ghana may be caused by",
A: "political stability",
B: "a favourable weather condition",
C: "low quality labour force",
D: "existence of large markets",
answer: "C. low quality labour force",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. An example of a capital resource is",
A: "mineral deposits",
B: "railways",
C: "managerial skill",
D: "fertile soils",
answer: "B. Railways",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. A planned development of a country’s human resource promotes the",
A: "efficient utilization of its capital resources",
B: "over-utilization of capital resources",
C: "neglect of its natural resources.",
D: "over-exploitation of its natural resources",
answer: "A. efficient utilization of its capital resources",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. The expression the independence of the judiciary means judges should",
A: "do whatever they like",
B: "appoint the Chief Justice",
C: "not pay taxes to the state",
D: "be free from political interference",
answer: "D. be free from political interference",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. Which of the following practices has a negative effect on the girl-child?",
A: "Puberty rites",
B: "Female genital mutilation",
C: "Ancestral worship",
D: "Initiation rites",
answer: "B. Female genital mutilation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. Among the Akans, the responsibility to select, nominate and install a chief lies in the hands of the",
A: "head of family and the traditional priest",
B: "traditional priest and queen mother",
C: "kingmakers and queen mother",
D: "family head and Asafo company",
answer: "C. kingmakers and queen mother",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. The term parenting refers to the",
A: "activity of bringing up children",
B: "state of giving birth to child",
C: "process of procreation",
D: "ability to maintain a healthy home",
answer: "A. activity of bringing up children",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. The country’s natural resources are not being fully tapped because of",
A: "lack of education",
B: "improved communication network",
C: "unemployment labour force",
D: "ability to maintain a healthy home",
answer: "D. ability to maintain a healthy home",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. Quantitative restrictions that a country imposes on its imports are known as",
A: "quotas",
B: "import duties",
C: "tariffs",
D: "import controls",
answer: "A. quotas",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. One of the practices which portrays national identity is",
A: "cultivating the same food crop",
B: "using a common currency",
C: "wearing identical clothes",
D: "using a common bank",
answer: "B. using a common currency",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. The most important source of power for domestic and industrial use in Ghana is",
A: "solar power",
B: "thermal power",
C: "hydroelectric power",
D: "liquefied petroleum gas",
answer: "C. hydroelectric power",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. The industry which has registered the most remarkable growth in Ghana in recent times is",
A: "manufacturing",
B: "agriculture",
C: "tourism",
D: "energy",
answer: "C. Tourism",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Fundamental human rights are claims which are",
A: "against the individual",
B: "natural to man",
C: "against the state",
D: "allowed by the law",
answer: "B. natural to man",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. Traditional festivals in Ghana are significant as occasions for",
A: "settlement of disputes",
B: "planning tribal wars",
C: "sharing stool lands",
D: "destoolment of chiefs",
answer: "A. settlement of disputes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. The contribution of the youth to national development is minimal because they",
A: "are trained to do only menial jobs",
B: "are too young to work",
C: "are denied participation in national programmes",
D: "lack a positive attitude to work and tend to act on impulse",
answer: "C. are denied participation in national programmes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. The constitution of a country refers to",
A: "the rules guiding the dissolution of parliament",
B: "the principles by which a country is ruled",
C: "the principles guiding the formation of political parties",
D: "rules governing the behaviour of the executive",
answer: "B. the principles by which a country is ruled",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. One of the most significant functions of the entrepreneur is",
A: "employment generational",
B: "dividend sharing",
C: "investment promotion",
D: "risk bearing",
answer: "D. risk bearing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. Ghana can prevent the dumping of inferior goods on its market by",
A: "liberalizing trade",
B: "imposing restrictions on imports",
C: "allowing competition",
D: "checking inflation",
answer: "B. imposing restrictions on imports",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. The entrepreneur is said to make profit when",
A: "total revenue exceeds total cost",
B: "marginal revenue is not equal to marginal cost",
C: "there is no difference between total revenue and total cost",
D: "the product is in great demand",
answer: "A. total revenue exceeds total cost",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. A government is said to be democratic if",
A: "the head of state is also the Prime Minister",
B: "all the legislators are nominated by the President",
C: "representatives are duly elected by the electorate",
D: "members of the executive are nominated by chiefs",
answer: "C. representatives are duly elected by the electorate",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. Stress and strain are characteristics of the adolescent period because generally",
A: "adolescents are expected to produce anything without much difficulties",
B: "Adolescents want to behave like adults",
C: "Adolescence is associated with marriage",
D: "Adolescence is associated with puberty",
answer: "D. Adolescence is associated with puberty",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. The process whereby the individual acquires some of his or her physical features from the parents is referred to as",
A: "identity",
B: "resemblance",
C: "heredity",
D: "inheritance",
answer: "C. heredity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. Which of the following is not an important purpose of a population census?",
A: "Determining the number of people in an area",
B: "Assessing the standard of living of the people",
C: "Providing information for drawing up development plans?",
D: "Determining how much taxes to impose on citizens",
answer: "D. Determining how much taxes to impose on citizens",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. Acceptable ways of behaviour in a society are called",
A: "sub-culture",
B: "deviance",
C: "heritage",
D: "norms",
answer: "D. norms",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. The rights of a citizen include  \nl. freedom from arbitrary arrest  \nII.	protection from slavery  \nIII.	payment of tax  \nIV.	Protecting public property",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and IV only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "III and IV only",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. A characteristic of a buoyant economy is",
A: "high inflation",
B: "low savings",
C: "high productivity",
D: "low standard of living",
answer: "C. high productivity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. Western education has partially failed to tackle the process of socialization in Ghana because of its emphasis on",
A: "development of values",
B: "acquisition of knowledge",
C: "character training",
D: "attitude training",
answer: "B. acquisition of knowledge",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. The problem of moral degeneration among the youth can be solved through",
A: "guidance and counselling",
B: "limited religious education",
C: "spending more time with peers",
D: "placing emphasis on foreign films",
answer: "A. guidance and counselling",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. Which of the following is a characteristic of rural societies",
A: "Each person fends for himself or herself",
B: "Rules and regulations are not strictly observed",
C: "Affairs of an individual are the concern of the whole community",
D: "Projects are usually undertaken on individual basis",
answer: "C. Affairs of an individual are the concern of the whole community",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. The rapid degradation of agricultural land in Ghana has been caused by  \nI.	overcropping  \nII.	afforestation  \nIII.	loss of soil fertility  \nIV.	widespread erosion",
A: "I and II only",
B: "III and IV only",
C: "I, III and IV",
D: "II, III and IV",
answer: "C. I, III and IV",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},



]